Ben Stolovitz

ben.stolovitz.com ben@stolovitz.com GitHub | LinkedIn

Summary

College junior pursuing degrees in CS and art with experience in accessibility research, computer graphics, and UI/UX design. I am agile, dedicated, and flexible. Academic & industrial background, including leading CS lectures and developing consumer-facing front-ends.

Education

Washington University in St. Louis

Bachelor of Science with major in Computer Science; minors in Art & Physics

CSE Outstanding Sophomore Award

Anticip. Grad. 2017 GPA 3.58/4.0

2015

Skills

Computer Languages

■ Fluent in PHP, HTML, CSS, C++, & Java; experienced in C#, Ruby, shell, Cmake & JS; used Python & Obj-C **Spoken Languages** English; conversational Spanish & Hebrew

Design Programs Adept at Photoshop & Illustrator; experience with Maya & Mudbox

Employment

Head TA, CSE102 Washington University in St. Louis

Sept 2014 — Present

Revamping introductory CSE courses with professor

St. Louis, MO

- Instructing code-skills classes and guiding students in assignments
- Training future TAs for planned massive roll-out (10 \rightarrow 70 \rightarrow 300 students)
- Writing, developing, & deploying novel course content

Frontend Development Intern, Hull.io

May 2015 — August 2015

• Designed & produced homepage illustrations

Atlanta, GA

Analyzed & implemented test protocols for ongoing development

Research Assistant, Georgia Tech Sonification Lab

June 2012 — May 2015

Designed undprecedented modular screen reader for web content

Atlanta, GA

Programmed audio-driven game for visually impaired 4th- and 5th-graders

Freelance Developer

April 2009 — Present

- Scripting Spotifious, a popular (35k+ views) Spotify controller for Alfred
- Writing Charles, a C++ ray tracer with refraction

Talks

Stolovitz, B., Batterman, J.M., & Walker, B.N. (2015). *Extending the CSS Mentality to Practical Rule-Based Screen Readers*. Presented at the 30th Annual International Technology and Persons with Disabilities Conference (CSUN 2015), San Diego, CA (March 4–6).

Activities

A cappella Marketing Chair and Tenor

Aug 2014 — Present

- Redesigning visual identity for The Aristocats, WUSTL's all-Disney a cappella
- Recording and producing multitrack recordings of live performances